Umar Rehman

West Ham, London

M: 0749 536 5471 E: <u>u.rehman_97@hotmail.co.uk</u>
<u>GitHub</u> <u>LinkedIn</u>

Profile:

Studied Astrophysics at University with courses that involved coding in Python for data management and simulations. Experience of working as a SEN Teacher Assistant developing communication and problem solving skills. Recently completed the Generation pre-apprenticeship Software Engineering bootcamp and have continued independently learning Python and C++. Actively pursuing entry level opportunities in Software Development.

Key Tech Skills & Qualities:

- Experience developing web applications using front end technologies including HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JS.
- Intermediate ability with Python and basic C++.
- Hands-on experience using GIT for source control, both on individual and group projects.
- Strong ability to self teach difficult technical concepts, confident in asking questions to clarify learning and understanding when needed.
- Strong leadership skills with the experience of supervising groups and delegating tasks.

Experience:

Tech Talent Accelerator, Generation, Software Engineering Student

04/2021 - 05/2021

- Understood the structure and attributes of web applications using HTML, CSS & Javascript.
- Applied the fundamentals of computer science and algorithms and learnt about and used Git for source control.
- Communicated on a team project to design an information website and worked using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap and delivered it within a day.

Teachers Assistant, SEN Teachers Assistant

08/2020 - 12/2020

- Provided one to one support for students (7-8) who have special education needs, such as Autism and ADHD.
- Supported the teacher with classroom management such as collating worksheets and texts
- Broke down complicated topics for students in order to help support their learning or understanding.

The Royal Household, Ticket & Information Assistant

05/2019 - 10/2019

- Processed telephone, internet and counter sales for visitors to the official residences of The Queen.
- Used the multiple computer systems in both the Contact Centre and at the sales counters to sell tickets and varying merchandise for all residences.
- Achieves targets for gift aid conversions, souvenir guidebook sales, e-Newsletter subscribers and cross-sales.
- Ensured that the booking information held on the computerised database is accurate and up-to-date.

 Undertook any other tasks delegated, as and when required, by the Summer Team Leaders and the Ticketing and Sales Management team.

Duke of Edinburgh Award Mentor, Volunteer Bronze Group Mentor

02/2015 - 05/2015

- Supervised and took responsibility for a group of 16 year olds; teaching skills such as navigation, teamwork, timekeeping & organisation.
- Created plans for the group's route and meals, leading them when required, and tested their problem-solving skills and initiative through situations I tailored for them.

KiPP2 Tuition Centre, London, Volunteer Tutor

12/2014 - 05/2015

 Worked with 14-15-year-old students studying for their GCSE examinations and periodically reviewed students' strengths and weaknesses to tailor a study program/method for each individual student.

Education:

Queen Mary University of London BSc in Astrophysics Completed modules: 09/2016 - 07/2019

Finished years 1 & 2 (left due to personal family reasons)

College of Haringey

11/2020 - 12/2020

Level 1 Warehousing

Level 2 Lift Truck Operator RTITB certified Reach and Counterbalance Lift Trucks.

Leyton Sixth Form College 09/2014 -06/2016

3 A-Levels: Chemistry (B), Mathematics (B), Physics (C)

Langdon Secondary School 09/2009 - 06/2014

9 GCSE's grades A to C, including Mathematics, English, Science

Interests:

- Computer programming and regularly update my knowledge by watching videos, reading articles and upskilling/developing existing skills through courses on LinkedIn Learning and Udemy.
- Public speaking as part of an online community and address subjects like media and literature.
- Received a Silver Duke of Edinburgh Award which encouraged a passion for hiking

References are available upon request